BG

B R E N D A G U T M A N

DATA AND BUSINESS ANALYST

615.920.9457

BRENDA.GUTMAN@GMAIL.COM

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/BMGUTMAN

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/BRENDAGUTMAN

PROFILE

The intrigue of unanswered questions has always been a fascination for me, which lead me toward my interest in science. I have found that data analytics is the perfect mixture of my interests in science and technology. Also, it aligns flawlessly with my talents, skills, and experience.

SKILLS

SQL(PostgreSQL): Joins, subqueries, CTEs, cleaning MS Excel: PowerPivot, pivot tables, lookup functions MS PowerPoint: Professional, informative, aesthetic Python: Jupyter Notebook, Geospatial analysis Power BI: Data modeling, Data interpretation, Maps Tableau: Visualization best practices Other: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, vector design apps

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

DATA ANALYTICS, BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATION
Nashville Software School | JUN 2021

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, MAJOR IN BIOLOGY University of Tennessee at Martin

GRADE IV WATER TREATMENT OPERATOR

TN Department of Environment and Conservation Water and Wastewater Operator Certification Board

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

ST. JUDE ROCK N ROLL MARATHON - NASHVILLE
Water Table Volunteer
CHILDREN FOR THE OCEANS
Research volunteer

AWARDS

NSS DATA VIZ COMPETITION | APR 2021 NCAA Women's Home-Court Advantage NSS Blog Post

EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | JAN 2021 - PRESENT

NSS is an organization that provides students with the knowledge and skills needed to succeed within the data and IT community.

- Clean, manipulate, and analyze data in SQL(PostgreSQL), Excel, and Python.
- Create simple, professional, and interactive dashboards using PowerBI and Tableau.
- Solve real-world problems and present solutions by working individually as well as in a virtual, collaborative team environment.

• <u>Low income & Elderly Assistance</u>: Finding the states in most need of financial assistance using pivot tables, chart visualizations, and dashboards in Excel.

- <u>App Recommendations:</u> Using SQL(PostgreSQL) to decide on the best apps to recommend to investors.
- <u>Visualizing Metro Nashville's Budget</u>: Finding inconsistencies and presenting them using PowerBI.
- <u>Prosperity in the United States</u>(Capstone): Calculate and visualize the rate of change in overall prosperity in the United States, using Python, and Tableau.

WATER TREATMENT PLANT TECHNICIAN

METRO WATER SERVICE | JUL 2017 - PRESENT

MWS provides drinking water to the citizens of Nashville, TN.

- Ensure the quality and safety of the drinking water distributed to Nashville by collecting and analyzing wet chemistry data.
- Analyze and interpret the graphics and trends using the plant's PLC and SCADA systems, ensuring proper functionality of the plant.
- Complete the daily water quality report to be summarized monthly before being reported to the state's regulatory office.
- Improve accuracy of reporting as well as saved company time by creating a spreadsheet to help operators perform the daily report.

LABORATORY SCIENTIST

EMPIRICAL LABORATORIES LLC | FEB 2017 - JUL 2017

EL provides chemical analysis of soil and water samples from across the United States.

- Performed wet and dry chemistry analysis, gathering quantitative data needed to correctly analyze samples to be reported to the customer.
- Reported data using the laboratory management(LIMS) system.
- Completed analysis for: pH, Conductivity, Total Solids, Total Dissolved Solids, Biological Oxygen Demand, Total Organic Carbon, and preparation for Metals testing, etc.

PRODUCTION TECHNICIAN

MERIDIAN LIFE SCIENCE | FEB 2014 - AUG 2016

MLS produces and supplies inactivated virus and antigens to medical and research facilities.

- Performed all procedures required to produce inactivated Rubella virus
- Created an Excel spreadsheet to accurately calculate inventory, personnel, and time needed to scale-up production to different degrees creating confidence in the department's ability to do so.